=> Difference b/w spring and spring boot

-> What is an Embedded Server in Spring Boot? and Uses?
   👉 Example: Like writing code → then copying the WAR file into tomcat/webapps folder → then starting Tomcat.

   When this runs, Spring Boot:(that means main code in application)
   Starts Embedded Tomcat.
   Deploys your REST APIs inside it.
   App is available at http://localhost:8080.

->  Q: Does Spring Boot replace Spring MVC, Spring REST etc …? 
    👉 No, Spring Boot does NOT replace Spring MVC, Spring REST, Hibernate, etc.

-> Q: Does Spring Boot run code faster than regular Spring code? Answer : No
    Spring Boot is just a framework on top of Spring.
    It provides auto-configuration, embedded server (Tomcat/Jetty), and starter dependencies. But the underlying Spring container, dependency injection, AOP, etc. are the same.
    Runtime execution speed: Same for Spring and Spring Boot.
    Developer productivity speed: Spring Boot is way faster 🚀.

-> Q: What are these files such as JAR, WAR files etc.?
    1. JAR (Java ARchive)
    A .jar file is like a zip file that contains compiled Java classes (.class files), resources, and metadata.
    Used to package Java libraries or standalone applications.
    Example: When you write a utility library and want to reuse it across projects, you package it as a JAR.
    Can also contain a META-INF/MANIFEST.MF file that tells which class has main() → so you can run it like:

    2.WAR (Web Application ARchive)
    A .war file is specifically for web applications.
    It contains:
   Java classes (.class)
   Libraries (/WEB-INF/lib)
   Configuration (web.xml)
   JSP/HTML pages
    Needs to be deployed on an external web server like Tomcat, JBoss, WebLogic.
   👉 Example: In old Spring MVC days, you packaged your app as myapp.war and deployed it in Tomcat.
   👉 With Spring Boot, you don’t need this — Boot embeds Tomcat, so you just run a JAR.


-> In pom.xml file there will be project name, version, JAR, WAR files like that
-> There will be dependencies also in that pom.xml

**************Difference b/w @Controller and @RestController ?*****************

-> If we use @Controller we should use @ResponseBody because if we wont give then it wont give JSON format
-> But in @RestController it will give automatically without using @ResponseBody

-> 📌 What is @ResponseBody in Spring?
  👉 @ResponseBody tells Spring "the return value of this method should go directly into the HTTP response body" instead of looking for a view (HTML/JSP page).
    By default, if you use @Controller, Spring assumes you want to return a view name (like JSP/Thymeleaf).
    If you want to return raw data (JSON, XML, String), you must use @ResponseBody.

-> Explore about the @RequestMapping clearly ?

-> Difference b/w @RequestMapping and @GetMapping see below:
| Feature   | `@RequestMapping`                                                 | `@GetMapping`                        |
| --------- | ----------------------------------------------------------------- | ------------------------------------ |
| Scope     | Generic (any HTTP method)                                         | Specific to GET requests             |
| Verbosity | Verbose (need method param)                                       | Short and clean                      |
| Use case  | When you want a single method to handle **multiple HTTP methods** | When you want to handle **only GET** |

-> so here for the extra logic and all na we have to use "Property"

✅ Recommended Priority for You

High Priority (Must finish first):

Core Spring Boot + Beans + DI + Scopes

JPA (CRUD + Relationships + Queries)

@Transactional

AOP

Web/REST Enhancements

Medium Priority (Next after above):

Async

Security Basics

JWT / OAuth

Low Priority (Optional / Later):

HATEOAS, Profiling, @ConditionalOnProperty

Microservices


     
=> Here mainly explore about the DAO, DataSource, EntityManager, JPARepository, CRUDOperations, etc these are there